准备好念每日警句吗
You ready to do our affirmations?
一定要吗
Do we have to?
好蠢
It's stupid.
听起来某人
Uh-oh, sounds like someone needs
要多点感恩之心哦
a little gratitude in their attitude.
欢乐洋溢在我的思想与生活中
Joy floods my thoughts and my life.
我的努力有整个宇宙的支持
My efforts are being supported by the universe.
不要  不要啊
Oh, no, no, no, n-n-no.
别坏啊  我求你了
No, don't break on me, I'm begging you.
拜托  继续走啊
Oh, come on, keep going,
你这堆废铁
you piece of crap!
无论发生任何事  我都能冷静对待
I respond peacefully in all situations.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：冰蓝      独醉
■
极品老妈  第一季第五集
时间轴：加森   校对&后期&总监：冰蓝
■
那个
So, uh,
我想你肯定很纳闷  我为什么会叫你过来
I bet you're wondering why I asked you to come over.
我知道自己期待着什么
I know what I'm hoping for.
我不会和你上床的
I'm not gonna sleep with you.
我需要一些帮助
I just need some help.
放心  我不是找你追讨
Don't worry, I'm not asking
你欠我的育儿费
for the child support you owe me.
太棒了
Awesome.
但我真的需要你把我借你
But I really need you to pay me back
买车的钱还给我
the money I lent you to buy the van.
好的
Oh, okay.
时机非常好  这笔钱我马上就能到手了
Well, your timing is good 'cause I'll have that money very soon.
就是说别指望了
So never.
我们说话这阵儿
I am, as we speak,
我已经处于稳赚生意的第二阶段
in phase two of a surefire business deal.
第一阶段是抽大麻看电视对吗
Was phase one smoking pot and watching TV?
你太了解我了
You know me so well.
听我说
Check this out.
几周前  我抽嗨了  在电视上看高尔夫
A couple weekends ago, I was stoned, watching golf on TV,
我发现了一件非常有趣的事
and I noticed something very interesting.
每段的广告都是壮阳药
Every other commercial is for boner pills.
好像他们知道白种老男人在看这个节目一样
It's like they know old white guys are watching.
你为什么看高尔夫
Why were you watching golf?
播音员轻声细语的  我觉得听着心里舒坦
The announcers whisper; I find it very soothing.
总之
Anyway,
我把埋在你家后院的三千块挖了出来
I took the $3,000 I had buried in your backyard...
我家后院之前埋了三千块吗
There was three grand buried in the backyard?!
这个不是重点
Not the important part of the story.
用心听
Follow me here.
我把所有药汇到了提华纳的药房[位于墨西哥]
I wired all the money to a Tijuana pharmacy
买了一万片山寨伟哥
and bought 10,000 knock-off Viagras.
我一早就会开车过去
I'm driving down there in the morning,
回来的路上  我会在所有经过的
and on the way back up I'm gonna stop
高尔夫球场停留
at every golf course I can find
十块钱一片  让白种老男人都再次雄起
and bone up old white guys at ten dollars a pop.
财源滚滚来
Ka-ching.
顺便问一下
Quick question.
把钱埋在我家后院
You don't make a habit of burying money
是不是你的习惯
in my backyard, do you?
我觉得这事跟你没什么关系
I'm not really sure that's any of your business.
妈妈  你在做什么
Mom, what are you doing?
想办法修车  宝贝
Just trying to get our car fixed, honey.
快回去睡觉
Go back to bed.
多谢你送我去开会
Thanks for taking me to the meeting.
客气什么
Of course.
给我记住了  如果我碰上了帅哥
Just remember, if I meet a cute guy...
我知道  我得自己想办法回家
I know, I know, I have to find my own way home.
告别酒精带来的绝症的康复阶段
Recovering from the fatal disease of alcoholism
不代表不能偶尔和陌生人来一炮
doesn't mean I can't get some strange every once in a while.
你应该把这话绣在枕头上
You should sew that on a pillow.
我得问你个问题
Listen, I have to ask you a question.
随便问  除非是关于你父亲的
Ask away unless it's about your father.
不是的
No, it's not.
我看到他时自然就会想起来
I'd know him if I saw him.
当然
Sure.
什么问题
So, what is it?
我讨厌这样做
Okay, well, I hate to do this,
如果不是到了山穷水尽的地步  我不会问
and I wouldn't if I wasn't really up against it,
有没有可能
but is there any way
你借我几千块
you could lend me a few grand
我月底还你
until the end of the month?
我的天
Oh, boy.
亲戚想借钱  总是这么尴尬
It's always so awkward when relatives ask for money.
亲戚
Relative?
我不是在脸谱网上追查你下落的远房表亲
I'm not some second cousin who tracked you down on Facebook.
我是你的女儿
I'm your daughter.
瞧  已经开始尴尬了
See, it's already uncomfortable.
拜托  你知道我有钱还的
Come on, you know I'm good for it.
-是吗  -妈
- Do I? - Mom!
我能帮肯定会帮  但我自己手头也紧
I would help you if I could, but I'm strapped, too.
我也是指望着薪水过日子
I'm going paycheck to paycheck.
好吧  多谢了
Okay, thanks.
我有个主意  可以为你争取些时间
You know, I do have an idea that might buy you a little time.
好啊  什么主意
Great, what is it?
不如我搬过去和你还有孩子一起住
Why don't I move in with you and the kids
共同支付开销
and we'll share expenses?
是啊  这也算个主意
Yeah, that is an idea.
我们就是室友啦
We'd be roomies.
是啊  室友
Yeah, roomies.
你怎么想
So, what do you say?
好难决定
Ooh, it's a tough one.
我说不  我就有可能破产无家可归
I say no and I might be broke and homeless,
流落街头  像狗一样找吃的
living on the street, scavenging for food like a dog.
我说好  就得和你一起住
I say yes and I'm living with you.
怎么样
So?
我在想
I'm thinking.
然后我想  真是疯狂  你不再喝酒了
Then I thought, "Well, that's crazy, you don't drink anymore."
但我抬头看  我已经站在酒水货道了
But I looked up, I was already in the beverage aisle.
既然我走过了整个商店
Since I had come all the way across the store,
看起来她情况不太好啊
Looks like she's having a tough time.
她穿着鲁布托的鞋子  拿着普拉达的包
She's got Louboutin shoes and a Prada handbag.
人家混得很好
She's doing fine.
你要纸巾吗
Do you want a tissue?
谢谢
Thank you.
马上回来
Be right back.
-等等  -什么事
- Wait. - What?
你好
Hi.
我是克丽丝蒂
Um, Christy.
好的
Okay.
好喜欢你的包
Ooh, love the purse.
谢谢
Thanks.
-等等  -又有什么事
- Wait. - What?
鞋子是鲁布托牌的吗
A-Are those Louboutins?
-是的  -太漂亮了
- Yeah. - Eh, gorgeous.
我也有过一双  但有次车着火
I had a pair once, but I had to ditch 'em,
我只能把鞋子扔掉逃命
running away from a car fire.
好刺激的一晚
What a night.
老天  你们酒鬼真能瞎聊
Boy, you drunks are a chatty bunch.
是啊  我们来这里就是为了聊
Yeah, well, that's what we do here--
分享英勇事迹
share war stories.
听起来真不错  但我不属于这里
Sounds great, but I don't belong here.
我不是酒瘾者
I'm not an alcoholic.
真有意思
That's funny.
我第一次来开会时  也是这种感觉
That's exactly how I felt my first meeting.
不  很明显你找到组织了
No, you clearly belong here.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我想我们可以请
Oh, um, I just thought that we could invite...
雷吉娜
Regina.
雷吉娜  出去喝杯咖啡
...Regina out for a cup of coffee.
真是不错
Oh, how nice.
我们为什么要这样做
Why would we do that?
我们应该互相帮助
We're supposed to help each other.
这是建议  不是规定
That's just a suggestion, it's not a rule.
雷吉娜  这是我妈妈邦妮
Um, Regina, this is my mom Bonnie.
你好
Hi.
你为什么要请我喝咖啡
Why do you want to buy me coffee?
瞧  诧异的人不止我一个吧
See, it's not just me.
我觉得你可能需要人谈谈心
I just thought you might need somebody to talk to.
我不需要
Yeah, well, I don't.
明白了
Got it.
抱歉打扰你了
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
好爱好爱好爱你的鞋子
Love, love, love the shoes.
等等
Hang on.
我想喝杯咖啡也无妨
I guess there's no harm in a cup of coffee.
见鬼
Aw, damn it.
你得原谅我的母亲
You'll have to forgive my mother,
如果你原谅了  拜托把方法传授给我
and if you do, please tell me how.
我醉得一塌糊涂
So there I am, drunk off my ass,
驾驶着偷来的割草机  开在五号高速公路上
driving down the 5 freeway on a stolen lawn mower
走的还是拼车道
in the car pool lane
光着上身
topless.
真是美好的时光
Oh, good times.
我也有一件好玩的事
I got one for you.
有天早上我走进厨房
I walked into the kitchen one morning
准备给家人做早餐  然后我意识到
to make my family some breakfast, and I realized,
这不是我的家  这些不是我的家人
"This isn't my house, that isn't my family.
我在温哥华做什么啊
And what the hell am I doing in Vancouver?"
我戒酒的原因就是
But the reason I stopped drinking is
我突然恐惧地意识到
because I came to the horrifying realization
我变成了我母亲那样的人
that I was turning into my mother.
什么意思
Hey.
-对不起  我伤了你的心吗  -是的
- Oh, I'm sorry, did I hurt your feelings? - Yes.
你毁了我的人生  我们扯平了
Well, you ruined my life, so we're even.
雷吉娜  跟我们讲讲你的事
So, Regina, tell us about you.
我没有你们这样的精彩故事
Oh, I don't have any stories like that.
我的童年很幸福
I had a great childhood,
很好的父母
great parents,
在学校表现也好
did well in school.
难怪你会在匿名戒酒
Hmm, no wonder you were having
互助会上精神崩溃
a nervous breakdown at an AA meeting.
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
我只是正经历一段难熬的日子
I'm just going through a tough time right now.
我的工作压力太大了
My job is really stressful.
我是资金管理人
I'm a money manager.
人们信任地将百万金额交给我管理
People trust me with millions of dollars.
另外  我正在离婚  闹得有些不可开交
And on top of that, I'm in the middle of a nasty divorce,
没错  也许我喜欢的缓解压力的方式
so yeah, maybe I like to take the edge off
就是一天下来  喝几瓶红酒
at the end of the day with a couple of bottles of wine,
几杯龙舌兰  再加一把肌肉松弛剂药片
a few shots of tequila... and a fistful of muscle relaxers.
那又如何
But so what?
每天清晨六点
Every morning at 6:00 A.M.
我会从地板上奋力爬起来
I pick myself up off that floor...
偷吃点孩子的利他灵
steal some of my kid's Ritalin...
[中枢兴奋药  治疗儿童注意力不足过动症]
重新开始新的一天
and start the day anew.
所以如果你们要拯救谁
So, if you need to save somebody,
就去拯救需要被拯救的人
go save somebody who needs saving.
因为我没有问题
Because I don't have a problem.
她说了  我们走
You heard her, let's go.
这太离谱了  我应该回家
This is ridiculous; I should go home.
我觉得你今晚不太适合
Yeah, I don't think it's a good idea
一个人待着
for you to be alone tonight.
会很好玩的  就像开睡衣派对一样
And this'll be fun-- like a slumber party
但是  是穷人们玩的
but, you know, for broken people.
我的车怎么办
What about my car?
没事的
It'll be okay.
我们早上再去取车
We'll, we'll get it in the morning.
好吧  我留下吧
All right, I guess I'll stay.
很好
Good.
你们玩得开心点  我们明天见
You two have a great time, I'll see you tomorrow.
你这是去哪里
Hey, where do you think you're going?
回家啊  我在自己床上睡才舒服
Home-- I sleep better in my own bed.
不同意你这说法的男人  我认识一打
I know a dozen men who think otherwise.
拜托  你也听她说了
Come on, you heard her.
她不太喜欢我
She's not very fond of me.
我就是喜欢她这点
That's what I like about her.
留下来
Now stay.
那
So,
客房在哪
where's the guest room?
就在这边
Right this way.
欢迎
Welcome.
好吧
All right.
我有单独的卫生间吗
Do I have my own bathroom?
我自己都没有单独的卫生间
I don't have my own bathroom.
在那边
It's over there.
-等等  -什么事
- Hold on. - What?
给我看看你的包
Show me the bag.
我不想
I don't want to.
给我
Give it to me.
妈  你在干嘛
Mom, what are you doing?
帮忙  给我
Helping. Give.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我经常招待朋友
I do a lot of entertaining.
有时我招待音乐家
Sometimes I entertain musicians.
那些是招待时预防受伤准备的
Those are for injuries sustained while entertaining.
-我现在能去尿尿了吗  -也许吧
- Can I pee now?! - Maybe.
你的乳沟里是什么
What do you got going on with your cleavage?
那是我身材好
I'm a full-figured woman.
是啊  我整晚都想骑着你  快给我
Yeah, and I want to motorboat you all night long. Now give.
可卡因
Ah, cocaine.
我真想念八十年代
I miss the '80s.
拜托  你三年前还在吸呢
Oh, please. You were doing it three years ago.
-行了嘛  -你可以去小便了
- We good? - You're free to urinate.
反正我现在在卫生间也没法做别的了
Not like there's anything else I can do in there now.
我们怎么处理这些东西呢
What are we gonna do with all this stuff?
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜把它们扔了
I guess just throw it away.
真的吗
Really?
我们不该留着  等着我重染毒瘾的那天吗
Shouldn't we save it for when I relapse?
妈
Mom.
拜托  我们都知道那天会来的
Oh, come on. We all know it's comin'.
"软饼干乐队"是什么
What is a "Limp Bizkit"?
那是一支乐队
It's a band.
我前夫试图通过
My ex-husband tried to get rich
售卖冒牌摇滚乐T恤来发家致富
selling counterfeit rock and roll T-shirts.
如果你喜欢的话  我车库里还有六千多件
If you like it, I've got 6,000 more in the garage.
这就行了
This'll do.
你知道卫生间在哪
Well, um, you know where the bathroom is,
厨房就在那边  如果你需要什么
the kitchen's right there and if you need anything,
我妈和我在那间卧室里
my mom and I are in that bedroom.
谢谢你
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
雷吉娜  我知道这对你来说很困难
Regina, I know this is difficult for you,
但我想告诉你  我觉得你做得很棒
but I just want you to know I think you're doing great.
真的吗  因为我觉得我可能会崩溃
Really? 'Cause I think I might snap
然后趁你和你妈睡觉时杀了你们
and kill you and your mother in your sleep.
你还真是不失幽默啊
Well, you haven't lost your sense of humor.
我可没有幽默感
I don't have a sense of humor.
好吧
Okay.
我得睁着一只眼睛睡觉了
Sleeping with one eye open.
安安
Night-night.
我睡这边的
That's my side.
我是客人
I'm a guest.
我不管  过去
I don't care. Move over.
那个惨女人怎么样了
How's the train wreck?
我不知道
I don't know.
-重点是  我们在行善  -是啊
- The point is, we're doing a good deed. - Yeah.
假设她不会崩溃  然后趁我们睡觉杀了我们
Assuming she doesn't melt down and try to kill us in our sleep.
你为什么要那样说
Why would you say that?
我开玩笑啊
I was kidding.
好吧
Okay.
晚安
Good night.
如果我们是室友
You know, if we were roomies,
那我们每晚都可以这样了
we could do this every night.
当然啦  如果我搬进来的话  会想...
Of course, if I moved in, I'd want to...
把这地方装饰一下
zhush up the place a little.
这里有什么不好了
What's wrong with it?
这里缺乏装饰
Eh, it lacks zhush.
装饰稀缺
It's zhush-less.
我觉得很舒适
Well, I think it's homey.
你还觉得能追上一个穿着运动裤的男人呢
Yeah, you also think you can catch a man with sweatpants.
克丽丝蒂
Christy?
进来吧
Come on in.
不好意思打扰了
Sorry to bother you.
没关系  出什么事了
Oh, no worries. What's up?
不告诉别人到底发生了什么事
I'm not gonna be able to sleep until I tell somebody
我睡不着
what's really going on.
好吧
Okay.
我看过一部拉拉黄片
I saw a lezbo porn movie
开头就是这样
start just like this.
我的问题比我说出来的大许多
I kind of got bigger problems than I let on.
财政问题
Financial problems.
没什么好丢人的
Oh, no shame in that.
我的车坏了  我没钱去修
My car just broke down, I can't afford to fix it
而我的信用卡债多到你没法想象
and I have credit card debt like you wouldn't believe.
真的吗  多少
Really? How much?
一万
Nineteen...
九千  块
thousand... dollars.
你真可爱
You are so cute.
想想三百五十万吧
Try $3.5 million.
什么
What?
我跟你说过
You know how I told you
人们信任地把钱交给我管理吧
people trust me with their money?
记得
Yeah.
他们不该如此
They shouldn't.
我挪用了客户的钱
I embezzled from my clients.
为什么
Why?
那是什么狗屁问题
What kind of question is that?
-那要问什么啊  -怎么做到的
- What's the better question? - How?
你得精通数学  同时长着一张大家信任的脸
You got to be good at math and have a face people trust.
梦想破灭了
And the dream dies.
总之
Anyway...
今晚我来这里的真正原因是
the real reason I came here tonight was...
我觉得警察可能在我家等我
I think the police might be waiting for me at my house.
会没事的
It's all gonna be okay.
你怎么这样说
How can you say that?
不是说给你听的  我是
Oh, not for you. I was...
自言自语
kind of saying it to myself.
什么
What?
我还以为自己深陷麻烦
I thought I was in trouble,
但听了你的故事
but, listening to you,
我发现我的问题很棒
I realized I have great problems.
我爱它们  我爱我的问题
I love them! I love my problems!
你说完了吗
You done?
是的  对不起  今晚的主角是你
Yeah. I'm sorry. Tonight's about you.
我只是激动了  你继续吧
I just got excited. Go on.
我不知道要怎么办才好
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
不管要面对的是什么
Well, whatever it is,
你都不必一个人承受
you don't have to go through it alone.
谢谢你
Thank you.
雷吉娜  等等
Regina, wait.
来吧
Come on.
睡这里
Snuggle in.
好吧
Maybe I will.
[模仿黄片音乐]
Bow chicka wow wow.
妈  沙发上怎么...
Mom, why is the couch all ma...
-妈  -啥事
- Mom. - What?
雷吉娜走了
Regina's gone.
好吧
Okay.
-醒醒  -啥事啊
- Wake up. - What?
-我们得去找她  -看在老天的份上
- We got to go find her. - Oh, for God's sake.
我们帮的还不够多吗
Haven't we helped enough?
她没开车  我们还能追上[抓住]她
She doesn't have her car. We can still catch her.
好吧
All right.
你觉得抓住她会有赏金吗
Hey, you suppose there's a reward for her capture?
-你真的会把她交给警察吗  -亲爱的
- You'd really turn her in? - Oh, honey,
如果赏金数额够大  我会把你也交给警察
if there was a big enough reward, I'd turn you in.
你觉得那是她吗
Do you think that's her?
我觉得那是不是她
Do I think that's her?
克丽丝蒂
Hey, Christy.
你去哪里
Where you headed?
加拿大
Canada.
得在那边过上新生活
Gonna build a whole new life there.
在加拿大可以被引渡回来
You know, you can be extradited from Canada.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
很确定
Oh, I'm positive.
那好吧
Okay, then.
去墨西哥
Mexico.
我告诉你吧  如果我偷了那么多钱
I'll tell you what, if I stole that kind of money,
我绝对会保证我有个
I'd make damn sure I had a getaway plan
不包括三轮车的逃跑计划
that didn't involve a tricycle.
你说得对  我该秀出大胸
You're right. I should've just whipped out my boobs
然后偷一辆割草机
and grabbed a lawn mower.
冷静  女士们  你俩都不好惹
Calm down, ladies, you're both gangsters.
太阳出来了
Hey, the sun's coming out.
[音乐剧《安妮》中的台词]
谢谢你  安妮
Thank you, Annie.
太棒了
How about that.
这是我十六七年里头一回
First time I've gone the whole night without a drink
整晚都没喝酒
in, like, 16, 17 years.
该死  我的确是个酒瘾者
Oh, damn, I am an alcoholic.
高兴点  监狱里有许多聚会
Cheer up. There's lots of meetings in prison.
我真的不喜欢你
I really don't like you.
没关系  我够喜欢我自己  把你的那份也带上了
That's okay. I like myself enough for the both of us.
你需要钱吗  克丽丝蒂
You need some money, Christy?
要啊  怎么
Yeah, why?
我还藏了一些钱
I still have some stashed away,
反正也是便宜了条子
and the Feds are just gonna take it.
让我帮帮你吧
Let me help you out.
真的吗
Really?
快答应
Do it.
天啊  我不确定
Gee, I-I don't know.
收下
Take it.
不  雷吉娜  我不想要你的钱
No, Regina, I don't want your money.
该死
Damn it.
其实也不是我的钱
It's technically not my money.
但还是...
Even still. It's just...
我帮你不是为了钱
It's not what this is about.
你是个好女人  克丽丝蒂
You're a good woman, Christy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还有邦妮
And Bonnie?
嗯
Yeah?
我想你知道我们的立场
I think you know where we stand.
我知道
I do.
你蹲监狱时  能把包包送我吗
When you go to prison, can I have your purse?
账单  账单  账单
Bill, bill, bill.
该死  我得和我妈妈住一起了
Oh, crap, I'm gonna have to live with my mother.
有空吗
Hey, got a minute?
有  进来吧
Sure, come on in.
后院有好多洞啊
Lot of holes in the backyard.
是啊  我打算抢你的银行
Yep, I was trying to rob your bank.
没必要了
No need.
谢谢你  墨西哥伟哥
Thank you, Mexican Viagra.
什么
What?
我跑出圣地亚哥球场之前全卖了
I sold all of it before I got out of San Diego.
太难以置信了
This is unbelievable!
那是你的一份
And that's just your share.
-还有更多的钱吗  -没了
- There's more?! - No.
知道吗
You know what? Uh...
我不管了
I don't care.
谢谢你  谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
我过来前吃了一粒
I took one before I came over
免得你真的很想感谢我
just in case you want to really thank me.
行  管他的呢
Sure! What the hell.